Iskren Ivanov

Software Engineer

A communicative and enthusiastic developer who likes finding creative solutions to complicated problems of any scope. Passioned about product development, data management and UI/UX. With more than 5 years of commercial experience as a Front End & Full Stack Developer from mature large corporate projects to Greenfield and POC projects.



			• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •	
IX.	iskren.	.dev@c	ımaıl	com

<u>Amsterdam</u>, Netherlands

in linkedin.com/in/iskrenivanov

github.com/IskIvanov

+31 6 42494693

iskren.dev

twitter.com/dev_iskren

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming	JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS (Technologies &	React, Next.js, Storybook, Redux,
Languages	SCSS/Less), Node.js, SQL, Java, Python	Libraries	RESTfull API, GraphQL, Context API,
			Styled Components , Material UI,
			Bootstrap, GreenSock, Pixi, React Native

Programming Object Oriented Programming and Testing Unit Testing, Integration Tesing, E2E

paradigms Functional Programming Testing

MethodologiesAgile, Scrum, Kanban, DevOps & CI/CDToolsGit, JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket, GitHub,

Visual Studio Code, Web Storm, IntelliJ IDEA, Postman, DevTools, Bash, Docker,

AWS, Firebase

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Engineer - FrontendBol.com

11/2021 - Present Largest e-commerce platform in the Benelux region.

Achievements/Tasks

Implemented complex technical solutions based on React and Typescript in the most visited webshop in Benelux.

- Developed unit, integration and end to end tests for different UI components and flows.
- Contributed and discussed code architecture and structure to improve overall readability, consistency and code scalability.
- Introduced new libraries and conducted demos to code owners on ways to implement them.
- Refactored older implementations and introduced new libraries to the codebase for better state menagment, data fetching and form handling eg. recoil, react query, zod, react-hook-form etc..
- Made small contributions on back end code, both on monolith codebase that acted as a middleware and bol.com micro services, worked with both GraphQL and Rest APIs
- Worked in an Agile environment, resolved bugs and shipped features to production after every sprint. Conducted code reviews and pair programming sessions. Acted as a Scrum Master for a sprint.
- Build multiple pages and UX flows within bol.com account that resulted in more than 200k eu. company savings.
- Contributed to bol.com design system and styleguides.
- Tech Stack: | Front End: React, TypeScript, Storybook, RTL, Design System. Back End: Java, Spring Boot, Kotlin. DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Gitlab CI |

Contact: Carlien Nijland - cnijland@bol.com

Utrecht

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer - Contract

Circularise

03/2021 - 11/2021 Netherlands

Circularise is a startup that brings transparency to global supply chains.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed a dashboard to easily create, maintain and transact digital assets for supply chain traceability system.
- Built a POC that integrated web3.js to interact with Ethereum blockchain.
- Developed multiple react application from the ground up and reused components.
- Integrated multiple libraries e.g. Okta, React Query, Formik.
- Analyzed health, maintainability and scalability of external npm packages e.g. licensing, contributors and community, to understand if
 it is a good fit for our project.
- Wrote technical documentation about features, components, and third-party libraries integrated into the system.
- Led ongoing product discussions with Circularise stakeholders and team members to clarify both businesses, technical and UI/UX requirements in order to improve UI flows and implement new features.
- Worked in an Agile environment, shipped multiple features after every sprint, and did a small demo to Circularise members and stakeholders.
- Consumed RESTfull APIs and collaborated with Back End Engineers on the development and improvements of API endpoints.
- Tech Stack: | React, TypeScript, Next.js, Material UI, Tailwaind., Styled Components, Storybook, React Query, GraphQL |

Contact: Kilian Marjew - kilian@circularise.com

Front End Engeneer - Freelance Greener Power Solutions

12/2020 - 02/2021 Amsterdam

Startup focused on delivering green energy from festivals to households.

Achievements/Tasks

- For this assignment I built a small MVP for Energy management system.
- Developed a UI from the ground up with React, TypeScript and Material UI.
- Integrated open-source libraries eg. Auth0, Formik, Graphana, GSAP and researched a few more to fit the use case of the EMS.
- Proposed, discussed and analysed UI solutions with Software Architect and CTO.
- Tech Stack: |React, TypeScript, Next.js, RTL, Material UI.|

Front End Engineer - Freelance

StakeLogic

05/2020 - 10/2020 Eindhoven, Netherlands

Game studio developing state of the art casino games.

Achievements/Tasks

- Build, expand and optimized the proprietary Stakelogic SDK written in TypeScript.
- Developed new innovative (2D/3D) game features using Pixi.js (WebGL library) and TypeScript.
- Contributed to the development of desktop tool for improving games layout using Electron and TypeScript.
- Integrated React and developed global react components to achive more maintainable and scalable UI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Accenture

01/2019 - 05/2020 Fortune 500 company. Sofia, Bulgaria

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on multiple e-commerce projects for major corporate clients which all were recognized for meeting client expectations.
- Contributed to a large codebase with reliable and scalable code.
- Heavily contributed to e-commerce rebuild, migrating from jQuery to React and TypeScipt.
- Contributed to numerous Back end services for a large e-commerce distributed application.
- Worked in an Agile environment with teams located in multiple countries within EU, following Scrum methodology.
- Delivered multiple features after every sprint and did demo to project stakeholders after each sprint.
- Worked within Agile team, shipped multiple features at the end of every spring. Did small demos after each sprint to customers and stakeholders.
- Proficiently troubleshoot simple and complex technical issues of any scope for differently assigned projects, optimized speed and scalability over a variety of web aplications.
- Tech Stack: | Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML/SCSS Backend: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL |

Front End Engineer - Games

SkywindGroup Ltd.

04/2018 - 12/2018

Sofia, Bulgaria

Global entertainment technology solution provider.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed and optimized Interactive Slot Casino Games and SDK.
- Worked closely with designers, animators and project managers to create new game features.
- Consumed RESTful APIs and discussed endpoint improvements with Back End engineers and mathematician.
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Fixed bugs in all stages of the development while taking ownership for features before and after deployment.
- Contributed to the development of a modular MVC SDK.
- Tech Stack: |TypeScript, Pixi.js, GSAP, Webpack, Node.js, Gulp, Jest|

Web Developer

Dantek Ltd.

02/2017 - 02/2018 Creative marketing agency. Sofia, Bulgaria

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed dynamic web pages using HTML5, SCSS, JavaScipt, jQuery and Bootstrap to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Introduces React to the workflow and helped other developers to understand it and create reusable UI components.
- Designed and Developed landing pages and email templates by utilising the latest UX standards and trends.
- Led collaboration efforts between marketing and design teams to develop innovative landing pages and emails.

SOFT SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

RSVP App

React Application for receiving responses from people interested in a particular event: https://github.com/lsklvanov/RSVPapp

Score Board App

• Simple scoreboard application build with React: https://github.com/lsklvanov/ReactScoreBoardApp

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Bulgarian Native or Bilingual Proficiency Dutch
Elementary Proficiency

CERTIFICATES

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals (06/2016 - 08/2016)

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Automation and Information Engineering Technical University of Gabrovo

09/2012 - 06/2016

Thesis

 Web Application for Holiday Planning https://github.com/lsklvanov/Holiday_planner 85% Overall Award Avarage

INTERESTS

Chess

Snowboarding

Cycling | Travel

Weightlifting